Guide to the Ernest Ropiequet Hilgard Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2000-164
  - Audiorecordings
    - AAAS – 136th meeting 34-69 session – Behavioral and Social Sciences – Session 1,1 of 2 - 1944, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - AAAS - 136th meeting 34-69 session – Behavioral and Social Sciences – Session 1, 2 of 2 – 1945, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Child Tape for Self-Use (For Holly) – JRH, 1975 Mar 5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Pain as Human and Scientific Problem – ERH –, 1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Broadcast: Rand, Collins, ERH, etc., "What is this Spell I'm in?", 1978 Mar 31; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Deep Relaxation (Commercial Tape), 1976; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Ind. Div. Suscept. To Hyp. ERH (McGraw Hill Sound System), 1968; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Watkins: Ego state therapy, 1977; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Watkins: Abreactive Techniques, 1977; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Simonton: Tape for patient: Relaxation and Therapy for Cancer – Sides 1&2, 1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Simonton: Role of the mind in Cancer Therapy – Sides 1&2, 1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Simonton: Role of the Mind in Cancer Therapy – Sides 3&4, 19781; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Simonton: (Includes Mrs. Simonton) – Side 5, 1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Restructuring with Hypnosis (clinical demonstration) – H. Spiegel and D. Spiegel, 1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Modular: Hypnosis with self-control; Modular: Relaxation/Desensitization., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21)
    - Hypnosis seminar - Stanford (sides 1 & 2), 1977 Dec 2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21)
    - Hypnosis seminar - Stanford (side 3), 1977 Dec 2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21)
    - Deep hypnosis. Jamie Newton, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - ERH Retirement Party, 1969; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 21, Folder 34)
      - Use copy, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 21)
    - Farnsworth and Hilgard: A Discussion of the Figures in Psychology, 1967; 22.01:22.06; 6 audiocassette(s) (Box 22)
    - Barber and Orne (session 1 & 2), Undated; 22.07; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 22)
    - ERH (Ernest R. Hilgard), 1984 Aug 7; 22.08; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 22)
    - CSICOP Conference 1991: Session 1, Controversies in Hypnosis, 1991 May; 22.09:22:11; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 22)
    - Etiology, Dynamics and Treatment of a Multiple Personality, 1982; 22.12; 1 audiocassette(s)
    - End the Cigarette Habit Through Self-Hypnosis (Folkways FX 6231), 1964; 1 phonograph record(s) (Box 22)
    - Lars-Eric Unestahl, Hypnosis (Blaton BTLP-006), Undated; 1 phonograph record(s) (Box 22)
    - David B. Cheek, Introduction to Hypnosis; Autohypnosis (Hypnosis Symposiums), Undated; 1 phonograph record(s) (Box 22)
  - Microfilm
    - Budzynski, Thomas H. "Feedback-induced Muscle Relaxation", 1 microfilm reel(s) (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Cambareri, John D. (1958) The Effects of Sensory Isolation on suggestible and non-suggestible psychology graduate students., 1 microfilm reel(s) (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Clyde, Dean J. (1947) Hypnotherapy and Phobias. M.S. Thesis, 1 microfilm reel(s) (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Hewitt, Jack L. (1965) A communications approach to the prediction and alteration of hypnotic susceptibility., 1 microfilm reel(s) (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Naruse, G. and Obonai, T. (1954, 1956) Japanese Psychological Research No.1, 21-33; No.4, 1-11, 1 microfilm reel(s) (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - Schulman, Robert E. (1962) Hypnosis and Verbal Learning., 1 microfilm reel(s) (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Current artwork (Box 23)
  - Charts: pain (Box 23)
  - Academic standing of undergraduates Oct. 1958-67 [confidential] (Box 23)
  - Age difference and susceptibility to hypnosis (Box 23)
  - Hypnosis study information (Box 24)
  - Protocols used for tests (Box 24)
  - [potential restrictions] (Box 24)
  - Hypnosis research experiments (Box 25)
  - Body positions study (Box 25)
  - Child hypnosis (Box 25)
  - [potential restrictions] (Box 25)
  - Hypnosis study (Box 26)
  - Personality tests, cats and dogs, pattern for ambiguity ? (Box 26)
  - [potential restrictions] (Box 26)
  - Hypnosis study (Box 27)
  - Personality tests, cats and dogs, pattern for ambiguity ? (Box 27)
  - [potential restrictions] (Box 27)
  - Hypnosis study materials (Box 28)
  - [potential restrictions] (Box 28)
  - Hypnosis study materials (Box 29)
  - Hypnosis study materials (Box 30)
  - Hypnosis study materials (Box 31)
  - Hypnosis study materials (Box 32)
  - Hypnosis study articles (Box 33)
  - WW-II 1942 Program Surveys (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Psychol. & the War 1942 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Psychol. & the War 1943 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Psychol. & the War 1944 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Income, Third Survey, Checked with Commerce Estimates (1944) (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - WW-II 1943-44 Off. of Civi. Reqmts. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - (miscellaneous loose materials, most dealing with 'Psychology and the War') (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Psychol. & the War 1945 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Psychol. & the War 1946 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Off. of Civil Reqmts. (OCR – 1944-45) (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Opinion Msrment (chapter-1946?) (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - OCR – 1944 Characteristics of the samples Interviewed in Consum. Surveys (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Population Statistics – Various 1943 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Soc. Sci. Res. Council (SSRC) – Ford Proj. Emotional Growth & Mntl Hlth. 1953 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - National Res. Council – 1946-1952 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Hypnosis – History: Am. Bd. of Examiners approval – 1961-1972 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Hypnosis – APA Div. 30, Psychol. Hypnosis 1970 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Berlin Educ. Program – Ford Foundation: International Affairs – 1964 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - L – correspondence – 1968-1970 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - History of Psychology Newsletter 1964 – January 1966 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Hypnosis – APA Div. 30 – 1969 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - J – correspondence – 1967-1969 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - (loose– The Psychological Bulletin, January, 1932) (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - APA History (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - (untitled volume – more about the psychology of World War II) (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Abbreviations of Periodicals (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - APA Card (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - (untitled volume – correspondence with various universities) (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Ann. Reviews Material (June 1990) (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Barabasz (1991) (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - Books: Save or Give to Library? (Box 34, Folder 31)
  - Bibliography (ERH) (Box 34, Folder 32)
  - Book Reviews (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - Budget (Box 34, Folder 34)
  - APA Centennial Book (Box 34, Folder 35)
  - Visiting Committee for the Department and Graduate School of Education at The University of Chicago 3/69 (Box 34, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence (Box 34, Folder 37)
  - APA Convention 1992 (Box 34, Folder 38)
  - CSICOP Controversies in Hypnosis (Box 34, Folder 39)
  - Disks Index 5/22/91 (office) (Box 34, Folder 40)
  - Delayed Reply (Box 34, Folder 41)
  - File Contents (Box 34, Folder 42)
  - Expenses (Box 34, Folder 43)
  - Gift Account (Box 34, Folder 44)
  - Gifted at Later Maturity – Sears/Holahan (Box 34, Folder 45)
  - Graph Paper (Box 34, Folder 46)
  - Hilgard – Bibliography (Box 34, Folder 47)
  - Hotel/Travel (Box 34, Folder 48)
  - Knoxville 9/90 (Box 34, Folder 49)
  - Kurtz – "On the SHSS:C" (Box 34, Folder 50)
  - Maps (Box 34, Folder 51)
  - NAS – 1992 (Box 34, Folder 52)
  - NAE – May 6, '93 (Box 34, Folder 53)
  - Necrologies (Box 34, Folder 54)
  - Obara, Y., Professor & VP Tamagawa Univ., Tokyo, Japan 1991 (Box 34, Folder 55)
  - Oslo 1994 (Box 34, Folder 56)
  - Piccione, Carlo 1993 (Box 34, Folder 57)
  - Projects on Problem-Solving, etc. May 1951 (Box 34, Folder 58)
  - Problem-solving, conclusive thinking, and decision-making (Box 34, Folder 59)
  - Psychological Science July 1992 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - SCEH Oct. '90 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Survey + Planning Comm. – Reports (empty) (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Sears: Obit Amer(ican) Psychologist (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Shepard – for Oshins (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Sears – Biographical II (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Hardback volume: Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scales, 1959-1967 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Paperback volume: Stanford Profile Scales of Hypnotic Susceptibility (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Paperback volume: National Academy of Science, Calving Perry Stone 1892-1954 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlet: Neodissociation Theory, Ernest R. Hilgard (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Talks + Papers 1970-1989 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - APA – Division 26 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - APA :: History Division 26 1980-1981 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Archives – History of American Psychology (Akron, Ohio) (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - APA :: History Division 26 1979-1980 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - American Psychology Association (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - APA – Handbook for Division Officers & other guides e.g. Media (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Am Psychol Convention 1980 Montreal Symposium, Expenses, & Introductions (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - APA :: Hypnosis, Division 30 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Loose papers: Hypnosis as an approach to personality (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Yellow Kodiak box: Math Learning (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Black binder: Psy 303 Seminar ERH (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - 15 loose paper packets, starting with 'References on Treatment of Overweight by Hypnosis', ending with pink 'Individualized Instruction' (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Psych. 170 (something illegible beginning with 'R') – Autumn 1972 (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - 10 loose papers, starting with 'Hypnosis: New Weapon in the Police Arsenal', ending with 'Campaign Countdown' (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - Psych. 160 (259) Hypnosis Wtr. 1978 (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Black untitled binder, first page inside: 'Source Amnesia' (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Thick pile of loose papers, starting with 'Proposal for the Seminar', ending with an untitled chart (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - Psych. 170 Records Autumn 1971 (side 1) / Psychophysics of Pain: JEP Paper in progress (Oct. 1971) (side 2) (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - Laurence, J-R, Perry, C & Kihlstrom, J The Hidden Observer Phenomenon in Hypnosis: An Experimental Creation? 6/81 (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - Psych. 160-259 Hypnosis (side 1) / Correspondence/Permissions (side 2) (Box 35, Folder 31)
  - Stanford Press (Box 35, Folder 32)
  - Psych. 170 Supplementary Material for Lectures (side 1) / Pain: Psychophysics Paper (Oct. 1971) (side 2) (Box 35, Folder 33)
  - 15 old overhead films (Box 35, Folder 34)
  - ERH Reprints 1928-1935 (Box 35, Folder 35)
  - 1936-1940 (Box 35, Folder 36)
  - 3 copies of 'The Bobbs-Merrill Reprint Series in the Social Sciences' (Box 35, Folder 37)
  - 2 copies of 'Educational Trends, a Journal of Research and Interpretations' (Box 35, Folder 38)
  - ERH 1941-1945 ERH (Box 35, Folder 39)
  - 1946-1950 (Box 35, Folder 40)
  - Reprints (Box 36)
  - Reprints (Box 37)
  - Reprints (Box 38)
  - Correspondence, A – S, 1989-90 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence, S – Z, 1989-90 (Box 40A)
  - Correspondence, A – S, 1990-93 (Box 40A)
  - Correspondence, S – Z, 1991-94 (Box 40B)
  - Correspondence, A – J, 1991-94 (Box 40B)
  - Correspondence, K – Z, includes photographs (Box 41)
  - Sport Psychology 1996 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Hypnotic Scale – Group Form C. (Bowers/Crawford Controversy) 1988 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Stanford University (H&S) J. Shoven, Dean 1993-1994 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Stanford University (general) (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Stanford University Libraries 1989-1990 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University Dept. of Psychology 1993-1995 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - School of Education SUSE External Relations 1995 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Sternberg, R.J. Yale re: ERH on Committee to select Hilgard Award recipients 1994-1995 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Suinn, Richard (U of Colorado, Dept. of Psychology) 1995 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - T – Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - ERH Todd & Morris (Review) Mod. Perspec. On Classic. & Contemp. Behaviorism. Greenwood Press, 1994 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Tsuchimochi, G.H., Ed.D., Ph.D. Prof. of Edu., Yokohama, Japan 1991-95 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - U – Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - UMI (University Microfilms Inc.) Ann Arbor, MI – J. Oberle – Books on Demand 1993 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - ERH Selection Comm. U. of Punjab Pakistan 1995 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - W – Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Wade, N. Univ. Dundee, Scotland 1993-1994 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Western Psychological Assoc. 1991-1995 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Wiener, Daniel ERH Foreword for bk. on B.F. Skinner (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - John Wiley & Sons, Inc. (Carol Beasley, Publisher) 1989-1994 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - U of Wisconsin Press Sheila Leary, Mktg. Mgr. re: D. Robinson's An intell. hist. of Psychol. 1995 (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - Yale Univ. 1992 (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - A – Miscellaneous 1994-1998 (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Academic Press 1993-1995 (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Ashen, Akhter 1993-1995 (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - Allyn & Bacon Simon & Schuster Ed. Grp: Wiener Review 1994-95 (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences 1991-1995 (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - O'Block, R. L. Am. Coll. Forens. Examiners 1996 (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - American National Biography (L. Watkins, Copy Chief) re: Hilgard, J.R. 1994-95 (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - American Philosophical Society 1992-1995 (Box 42, Folder 30)
  - APA General File 1991-1995 (Box 42, Folder 31)
  - APA Div. 1 (R.J. Steinberg, Pres.) 1994-1995 (Box 42, Folder 32)
  - APA Div. 2 Tchg. of Psych. 1993-1995 (Box 42, Folder 33)
  - APA Div. 20 1992-1995 (Box 42, Folder 34)
  - APA Oral History Committee Div. 26 1993-95 (Box 42, Folder 35)
  - APA Div. 30 1994-1995 (Box 42, Folder 36)
  - APA Obituaries (James L. Pate, Ph.D. Hist. & Obit Ed) 1996 (Box 42, Folder 37)
  - APA Obituary (L. Benjamin, Ed.) 1994-- (Box 42, Folder 38)
  - APA Ethical Standards of Psychologists: A Summary of Ethical Principles (Box 42, Folder 39)
  - APA Science Directorate 1994-95 (Box 42, Folder 40)
  - Amer. Psychological Fdn. 1995 (Box 42, Folder 41)
  - American Psychological Society 1995 (Box 42, Folder 42)
  - Annual Reviews Inc. 1995 (Box 42, Folder 43)
  - Amer. Soc. of Clin. Hypnosis 1992-1995 (Box 42, Folder 44)
  - Australian Soc. of Hypnosis (G. Coman, Fed. Treasurer), Heidelberg, VIC 3084 1994-95 (Box 42, Folder 45)
  - B – Miscellaneous 1994-1998 (Box 42, Folder 46)
  - Banyai, Eva Eurohypnosis, Congress 1996 (Box 42, Folder 47)
  - Benjamin, Dr. Ludy T. Texas A&M, Austin 1993-95 (Box 42, Folder 48)
  - Benton, Stephen, Ed. Edu. Psychol. Review 1995 (Box 42, Folder 49)
  - Berliner, D., Ph.D. Arizona St. U. re: Handbook 1993-1995 (Box 42, Folder 50)
  - Books in Rooms 206, 208 1996 (Box 42, Folder 51)
  - Bringmann, W.G. U. South Alabama "Pictorial History of Psychology" Introduction by ERH 1995 (Box 42, Folder 52)
  - ERH: British Psychol. Society U of London 1995 (Box 42, Folder 53)
  - Brit. Soc. Exper. & Clin. Hypnosis (ERH – member) 1995 (Box 42, Folder 54)
  - Brown, Rhonda Texas Tech U. Lubbock, TX Oct. 1998 (Box 42, Folder 55)
  - Brunner/Mazel, Inc. Re: publ. Hilg & Hilg Hypn. in Relief of Pain 1993-1995 (Box 42, Folder 56)
  - C – Miscellaneous 1993-1998 (Box 42, Folder 57)
  - Calendar of Commitments 1989-1995 (Box 42, Folder 58)
  - Capshew, J. Corres., Recomm. ltr. 1992-95 (Box 42, Folder 59)
  - Cassell, R.N., Ed.D. Chula Vista, CA (Project Innovation) 1995 (Box 42, Folder 60)
  - Cheiron (Internat'l Soc. for Hist. Behav. & Soc. Sci.) 1995 (Box 42, Folder 61)
  - ERH Cold Pressor (diagram) from Heart Rate Article – continuing file (Box 42, Folder 62)
  - (untitled folder – first page is a yellow 'Service Repair Order' receipt) (Box 42, Folder 63)
  - Coon, Deborah J., Ph.D. U New Hampshire 1995 (Box 42, Folder 64)
  - Costello, Brian R., Ph.D. Australia 1994-1995 (Box 42, Folder 65)
  - Crawford, H.J. Virginia Polytech Inst. & State Univ. 1989-1995 (Box 42, Folder 66)
  - D – Miscellaneous 1994-1998 (Box 42, Folder 67)
  - Divided Consciousness (request to publish in Italian) 1997-98 (Box 42, Folder 68)
  - Dewsbury, D., Ph.D. U of Fl. – Gainesville 1993-95 (Box 42, Folder 69)
  - Dictionary of International Biography 1996 (Box 42, Folder 70)
  - E – Miscellaneous 1993-1998 (Box 42, Folder 71)
  - Encyclopedia of Psychology (Foreword) R. Corsini (Box 42, Folder 72)
  - Encyclopedia of Psychology, APA Art. re. Carr & Sears – ERH 1997 (Box 42, Folder 73)
  - F – Miscellaneous 1991-1998 (Box 42, Folder 74)
  - Fan Letters 1993 (Box 42, Folder 75)
  - Freyd, Pamela & Peter 1991-1995 (Box 42, Folder 76)
  - Frick, W. B. re ERH Statement: Most influential articles in history of 20th century psychology, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Fromm, Erika, 1994-95 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - G – Miscellaneous 1993-98 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Gauld's "A history of hypnotism" rev. by ERH Contemp. Psychol. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Gift account (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Griggs, Prof. R. A. 1995-97 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Glaser, Robert, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - H – Miscellaneous 1993-98 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Hall, James, M.D. 1995-96 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Harcourt Brace (Sarah Smith, Sr. Developmtl. Ed.), 1994 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - ERH Plenum Publishing 1996 "Perspectives on Educational Psychology" (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Ernest Hilgard fellowship fund, 1990-92 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Hilgard, E. R. – biography and curriculum vitae (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Hilgard honors (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - ERH: History of Psychology textbook (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Hilgard memoirs: materials for, 1989-2000 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - ERH television interview with Shinsuke Shimojo, U of Tokyo, Japan (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Hilgard, permissions to cite, quote, publish and copyright, 1994-96 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Hilgard, Henry, 1993-2000 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Hogg foundation, Austin, TX, Wayne Holtzman, 1990-94 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Holroyd, J., 1999 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Hoover Institution (Theron Alexander) 1994-95 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Hoskovec, Jiri (George) Wurzburg talk, 1994-95 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Hypnosis reprints (bound) 1993 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - I – Miscellaneous, 1993-98 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - International Society Hypnosis, 1994-99 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - International Union of Psychol. 1996 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Invitations to speak, write, etc., 1993-05 (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Izawa, Chizuko, 1990-95 (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - J – Miscellaneous 1991-98 (Box 43, Folder 30)
  - Jaeger, Alfred, (re journals for sale) 1989-95 (Box 43, Folder 31)
  - Josephson, T., 1991-92 (Box 43, Folder 32)
  - New Ideas in Psychology, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 33)
  - K – Miscellaneous, 1993-98 (Box 43, Folder 34)
  - Kalawan, Lorna (Intech Group) 1995 (Box 43, Folder 35)
  - Kayashima, Atsushi, request re WWII Japan Education, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 36)
  - Kihlstrom, J. H., 1993-95 (Box 43, Folder 37)
  - Kimble, G. 1991-99 (Box 43, Folder 38)
  - L – Miscellaneous 1991-98 (Box 43, Folder 39)
  - Leary, David E., 1991-95 (Box 43, Folder 40)
  - Learning Initiative, 1995-98 (Box 43, Folder 41)
  - Lubinski, David, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 42)
  - M – Miscellaneous, 1992-98 (Box 43, Folder 43)
  - Mac, Mc – Miscellaneous 1993-96 (Box 43, Folder 44)
  - MacMillan, M. B., 1991-96 (Box 43, Folder 45)
  - Marks, D. F., 1995-96 (Box 43, Folder 46)
  - Master Work Series, re Divided Consciousness reprinting, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 47)
  - McManus, Fred, 1990-95 (Box 43, Folder 48)
  - McNab, Beulah, 1993-85 (Box 43, Folder 49)
  - ERH: Bio on Quinn McNemar, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 50)
  - MIT Press, 1994-95 (Box 43, Folder 51)
  - Morgan, Arlene, 1995-98 (Box 43, Folder 52)
  - N – Miscellaneous, 1994-99 (Box 43, Folder 53)
  - Nadon, R. Spec. Conf. On Hypnosis, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 54)
  - National Academy of Education, 1995-99 (Box 43, Folder 55)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1995-2000 (Box 43, Folder 56)
  - National Academy of Sciences, regional round table meeting, 2/6/1995 (Box 43, Folder 57)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 58)
  - NBC television re hypnosis (Lynisi Weeks) 1994 (Box 43, Folder 59)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1993-94 (Box 43, Folder 60)
  - O – Miscellaneous 1993-98 (Box 43, Folder 61)
  - Office budget and statements, 1990-94 (Box 43, Folder 62)
  - Office expenses, 1989-94 (Box 43, Folder 63)
  - P – Miscellaneous, 1994-95 (Box 43, Folder 64)
  - Protocol for hidden observer (Box 43, Folder 65)
  - Psychologists I have known, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 66)
  - Miscellaneous talks and lectures in pressboard binders (Box 44)
  - Hypnosis research v. 1 (Box 44)
  - Hypnosis research v. 2- v. 6 (Box 45)
  - Hawthorne House memoranda v. 1 – v. 2 (Box 45)
  - Hawthorne House memoranda v. 3 – v. 6 (Box 46)
  - Pain reprints (Box 46)
  - Research Reports on hypnosis (Box 46)
  - Financial reports (Box 46)
  - Hilgard family (Box 47)
  - Hypnosis (Box 47)
  - J. Hilgard material (Box 47)
  - Stanford Scales of Hypnotic Susceptibility, ASCH Press republication, 1994-99 [1 folder] (Box 48)
  - Staff Seminars, Laboratory of Hypnosis Research, Autumn 1977-78 [1 binder] (Box 48)
  - Creative Stories under Hypnotic Regression [sessions with John Hanbery], 1973 [1 binder] (Box 48)
  - Josephine R. Hilgard, Financial History in Laboratory of Human Development, 1954-58 [1 binder] (Box 48)
  - Laboratory of Hypnosis Research, Hawthorne House, Project Status Reports, Oct. 1964-Sept. 1979 [1 binder] (Box 48)
  - Photocopies (3) of Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale Forms A and B and photocopies (2) of Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale Form C [in Kinko's box] (Box 48)
  - Photographs, including one of Frank Angell, 1927 (Box 49)
  - Framed photograph of Hilgard and Al Hastorf (Box 50 os)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2007-286
  - Bound set of Hilgard's reprints 1925-1993 (10 volumes) (Box 1)
  - Hilgard's Ph.D. dissertation "Conditioned Eyelid Reactions," Yale University 1930 (Box 2)
  - Bibliography and CV (Box 2)
  - "History of the Department of Psychology" [Stanford], April 1981 (Box 2)
  - Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale – photocopies from the published work (Box 2)
  - Original blank forms and scoring booklets (Box 2)